I am a knight.
A knight is their blade.
And that blade is I.
I'm starting to understand that saying,
and why the word "person"
isn't included in it.
Yatori, do you think I am flame?
Huh? You're just you, Shia.
My one partner in the world.
Then I don't think you're a blade, either.
You're worried about me? Thank you.
It's all right.
I don't know if I'll ever reach
that state again, to be honest,
but remember how quickly
he just knocked me down
from the level of mastery
I'd worked so hard to reach?
As long as I'm around him,
I'll never completely become a blade.
It's been that way since back then.
Studying abroad?
General Bada Sankrei told me himself.
So, what will you do?
I'll go.
I hear he's at the forefront
of all military matters.
If you want to do it,
then it's settled.
Go study hard.
But, no matter what you learn,
don't forget that you're an Igsem.
Welcome to the world of science!
Two in One
Katjvarna Empire
Rising Sun Regiment Garrison
General Bada Sankrei.
Call me Uncle Bada.
What is it, Yatorishino-chan?
What's that all about?
I'm sending my son up to fly.
As far as I can tell,
that balloon is very similar
to the ones used in Kioka.
Want to try, too?
If you order me to, then gladly.
I see.
You're Solvenares Igsem's daughter, all right.
What does that mean?
It means I underestimated his
style of education a little.
Don't worry. It's my problem, not yours.
My name is Anarai Kahn.
I'm...
well, you could call me the
representative of these scientists.
"Scientists?"
Call me Dr. Anarai!
Oh, Ikta!
Take over for me.
Sure, leave it to me.
Dr. Anarai, what is that?
Egg yolks, milk, sugar, some cinnamon.
Those have been mixed and added to
a vessel filled with frozen saltwater.
Doctor, may I ask something?
Go ahead.
What is science, exactly?
Very well.
I'll start by describing a discussion
I had with a priest when I was younger.
Nazuna, two cups of tea.
Come on, Brother Bajin.
Keep shaking!
Why do I have to do this?
So, that's how it is.
Got it?
There were several words
I wasn't familiar with,
but I understood the gist.
"Science" is a field that attempts to
explain things that are, in theology,
explained as "acts of God,"
from another approach.
She's pretty smart.
Yes, I'm surprised, too.
Now try eating it.
All right.
Want some more?
Well, "God"?
Can't make this flavor, can you?
Sorry.
Swordfighting isn't really my thing.
I'm sorry.
I was so focused on my training
that I almost injured you.
Well, I'm the one who interrupted you.
Anyway, can you do something
about the way you talk?
Is the way I talk strange?
It's not strange, but it's stiff.
Stiffer than bricks!
Even if you're using proper etiquette,
shouldn't you try and be more casual
with kids your age?
I've actually never met anyone else my age.
I can't even imagine what that must be like.
So basically, you don't know
how to play, do you?
Why don't you come play with me for a bit?
Dad gave me this, you see.
What is this?
Mission one:
Make Major Guihan fall into a hole.
He always comes by this way when
he washes his face in the morning.
Just like I thought!
A real hole next to a fake dummy one!
Don't think you can make me fall
for the same trick over and over!
I was sure you wouldn't find out.
Now, since I've seen through
your trap, today you're—
Yes!
If two holes isn't enough, I'll use three!
So, mission one is complete.
We've got four more similar ones.
Our next mission is risky.
We just have to get
the ingredients out of the kitchen,
but the kitchen is guarded
by a fierce protector.
Chief Cook Mariban Susa, or Old Lady Mari.
We have to get past her.
Let me do it, please.
So, you're the guest everyone's talking about?
Old man Anarai's been talking about
nothing else since yesterday.
I wanted to see how the cooking was done.
It's nothing special.
We just make good food, fast,
and in large quantities for hungry soldiers.
You're amazing.
It all landed on top of the straw.
As long as you know
an object's weight and shape,
you can throw it in a clean arc by
adjusting the strength of the toss.
It's a simple application
of artillery mechanics.
It's like I've got a new friend
I can rely on!
This is my house!
May I come in?
I'll ask you instead,
why couldn't you?
Mom, I'm back!
Welcome back, Ikta.
Welcome.
I'm Y-Yatorishino Igsem.
I've been accompanying your son today.
I'm Yuhka.
Ikta's mother.
Thank for playing with my son.
N-Not at all.
I brought you a lot of things,
just like dad ordered.
Most of it was thanks to Yatori, though.
Lunch will be ready soon.
Go play with Ikta until it's served.
No, I...
Can you play chess?
Yes,
I learned it as part of my officer training.
Let's play a game, then!
I'm back.
I'm so hungry.
Oh, you're here, Yatori-chan.
Thank you for having me.
Did you succeed in your mission today?
Sure, but...
This is Yatori's first time, so go
easier on her, you dumb old man.
That's amazing.
You're both using castles
in a really close game.
Okay, lunch is served.
Do you live here with your family,
General Sankrei?
Yeah. I didn't want to leave them behind
to get transferred a bunch of places.
As long as I'm here, Mom will be fine.
So go where you want, old man.
Don't make Uncle Shiba and Uncle Rikan
do all the running around.
Don't try and fool me, son.
I know you'd be lonely without me.
Nope. Not at all.
Yatori-chan, let's all make
pumpkin cake later.
We need to give something back
to Mariban for what we borrowed.
Right.
Okay! Mission: Catch the Biggest Fish
in the Swamp is complete—
You're going to become a soldier, huh?
Yes. I'm going to officer's school.
I see.
That's not bad,
but why not be a scientist like me?
A scientist?
The two of us could work together
and go around unraveling
all the world's mysteries.
Like monsters and stuff.
Why not think about it?
There's no point in thinking about it.
I'm following the path of the soldier.
That's been decided from the start.
That doesn't make sense.
What's important is whether
you want to do it or not, right?
It makes sense.
I was born as an Igsem.
I know what I should be.
That's all.
I can't accept that.
There's no need for you to accept it.
There sure is.
Without you, the monsters
are going to eat me.
Sorry to drag you on a boring
expedition like this.
No, it's fine.
The two of you have been doing
nothing but military exercises lately.
We've been a little lonely.
But it has been a while, hasn't it?
We usually have soldiers trailing behind us.
It feels like I should have
more weight on my back.
We're doing a geological survey, too?!
You didn't forget the
surveying tools, did you?
I did...
You dummy!
Thanks to Brother Bajin,
we've got a whole day to ourselves.
Oh, Yatori.
Did you find an ax—
Y-Yatori...
Th-That scared me...
I didn't know there were wolves
so close to the base.
They're all skin and bones.
The drought's been going on for a while,
so they must be hungry.
That's why they've come to a place
they wouldn't normally be.
Is he the leader, perhaps?
It's possible for us to just stay in here,
but they might attack Brother Bajin and
his group when they return tomorrow.
So other than your two swords,
these are our weapons, huh?
Killing or driving away
all the wolves around the shed.
That'll be our mission this time.
The time limit is 9:00 A.M. tomorrow.
Any objections?
None.
Let's come up with a plan.
A hit, but not a fatal one.
They're breaking the back wall!
So this side was a decoy?
They're getting further away.
Think they'll give up?
We've told them that any attempts
they make are going to be costly.
Now it comes down to how hungry they are.
The leader of the pack
seemed exceptionally smart.
That's why we can't be too careful.
If he didn't give up,
who knows what he'll do next?
If we could talk to them,
we could've worked something out.
Even humans only start negotiating
once the bullets have run out.
My dad once told me those two things
would never happen in the opposite order.
Hit to the head.
One's down!
Roger.
The two in the front are
staying away from the door.
We knew they'd come after what looked
like the weakest point, but...
If you become a soldier,
are you going to be doing this all the time?
My second shot missed.
Did you say something?
Nothing.
I took one out, too.
Ikta!
Don't move.
If you aren't behind me, you'll probably die.
Yeah. I know.
I'm glad I got this ready.
Maybe we could talk to the leader.
He's that smart.
You talk a lot when you're worried, huh?
Don't point that out so calmly.
You're going to make me cry.
I know how you feel.
I'm scared, too.
But I'll send you back alive,
even if it costs me my life.
I'm an Igsem, after all.
What?
That wasn't in the plan.
I mean if things get really bad.
It's better that one of us live
than both of us die.
No!
Anything that doesn't end in us
both going home is equally bad.
If you don't understand that, you're a fool.
You're the fool.
You have to make hard decisions—
There's one thing I've learned
over the past few weeks.
If you and I work together,
we can get through anything!
Yatori, we only have the
two of us to rely on.
The two of us have to become one
and solve this together!
It's the only way to win.
Like a right and left hand,
or the right and left brain,
let's be a pair of organs
moving with one will.
Don't forget: no matter what, I'm your
left hand, and I'm here for you!
If I'm the right hand,
you'll have to live up to being my left.
Execute clean-up operation!
It hit!
Ow...
Two left.
Did we drive them off?
One of them was that leader.
It's too early to make assumptions.
There he is!
Sorry.
That's all the spices we had.
Yatori!
Are those reinforcements?
Well, I might lose if I was on my own, but...
Looks like it's over.
Yeah.
This is the last one.
Let's take our time eating it.
What are those wolves going to do now?
Their leader was badly wounded.
They're going to have a hard time, I bet.
I feel like I'm eating their meat.
Yeah.
I was thinking the same thing.
You know, Yatori,
if you're capable of imagining that,
you could be something other than a soldier.
Take your time thinking about it.
Just remember what I said today.
If it's paired with a violent
memory like what just happened,
you'll never forget, right?
You're right.
I'm probably never going to forget this.
After that, Uncle Bada was imprisoned,
and Ikta and Yuhka-san went missing.
But...
Ikta came back to me.
I came to take you, Yatori,
from this land without a future.
Next time: At the Base of the Stairs of God.
At the Base of the Stairs of God.